Wallace Lyman Orcutt student notes from Yale University School of Medicine
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
Wallace Lyman Orcutt student notes from Yale University School of Medicine
1908-1910
Ms Coll 22
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
1
(2 boxes, containing 12 notebooks)
The notebooks contain Orcutt's notes from medical school courses including physiology courses by Russell Chittenden and Yandell Henderson, pathology, bacteriology, pharmacology, histology, therapeutics by Oliver T. Osborne, and clinics by George Blumer and Wilder Tileston. The histology notes contain illustrations colored in pencil. The bacteriology notes are in an illustrated notebook printed especially for the bacteriology course at Yale. The physiology notes contain tracings from a kymograph or similar device.
Orcutt, Wallace Lyman, 1883-1950
Biographical / Historical
Wallace Lyman Orcutt was born in Sutton, Vermont in 1883. He graduated from Yale University School of Medicine in 1911, and served as a general practitioner in West Newbury, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents
The notebooks contain Orcutt's notes from medical school courses and laboratories including physiology by Russell Chittenden and Yandell Henderson, pathology, bacteriology, pharmacology, histology, therapeutics by Oliver T. Osborne, and clinics by George Blumer and Wilder Tileston. The histology notes contain illustrations colored in pencil. The bacteriology notes are in an illustrated notebook printed especially for the bacteriology course at Yale. The physiology notes contain drawings and tracings from a kymograph or similar device.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Medical education; Medical students; Notebooks; Blumer, George, 1872-1962; Chittenden, R. H. (Russell Henry), 1856-1943; Henderson, Yandell, 1873-1944; Osborne, Oliver T. (Oliver Thomas), 1862-1940; Tileston, Wilder; Yale University. School of Medicine; Tileston, Wilder
- Notebook: Physiology taught by Russell Chittenden, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Notebook: Physiology/ Pharmacology, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Notebook: "Physiology and Experiments" taught by Yandell Henderson, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Notebook: Chemical Laboratory (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Loose notes on chemistry (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Notebook: "Histology Lab" (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notebook: Embryology Lab (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Notebook: Embryology / Physiology, 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Notebook: Bacteriology and Pathology, 1908-1909 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Notebook: Bacteriology Laboratory, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  These notes are entered in a printed manual by "Yale University, Department of Medicine, Bacteriological Laboratory."
- Notebook: "Pathology Recitations" (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Surgical Dressings Demonstrated, Junior Class" (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Two mimeographed sheets.
- Small notebook on diagnostic tests, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Notebook: Medical Clinics by George Blumer and Wilder Tileston / Therapeutics by O. T. Osborne, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 8)